《哈利波特与火焰杯》
Bloody kids.
该死的孩子
How fastidious you've become, Wormtail.
你怎么变得这么挑剔了，虫尾巴？
As I recall, you once called the nearest gutter pipe home.
如果我没记错 你不久前还以阴沟为家呢
Could it be that the task of nursing me has become wearisome for you?
是你伺候我觉得烦了吧？
Oh, no. No, no, my Lord Voldemort.
哦，不，不，伏地魔主人
I only meant...
我只是说...
...perhaps if we were to do it without the boy.
...或许我们没有那个男孩也行
No! The boy is everything!
不，那男孩就是一切！
It cannot be done without him. And it will be done.
没他成不了事 肯定会成功的
Exactly as I said.
就和我说的一模一样
- I will not disappoint you, my Lord. - Good.
- 我不会让你失望的，主人 - 很好
First, gather our old comrades.
首先，把我们的旧部召来
Send them a sign.
给他们发信号
Nagini tells me the old Muggle caretaker...
娜吉妮告诉我那麻瓜老看门人...
...is standing just outside the door.
...正站在门外
Step aside, Wormtail, so I can give our guest a proper greeting.
靠边站，虫尾巴 让我好好问候一下我们的客人
Avada Kedavra!
[咒语]
Harry.
哈利
Harry!
哈利！
Are you all right?
你还好吧？
Hermione. Bad dream.
赫敏...我做了个噩梦
- When did you get here? - Just now. You?
- 你什么时候到的？ - 刚才，你呢？
Last night.
昨晚
Wake up! Wake up, Ronald!
醒醒！醒醒，罗纳得！
Bloody hell.
真要命
Honestly, get dressed.
求求你，穿好衣服
And don't go back to sleep.
别再睡了
Come on, Ron! Your mother says breakfast's ready!
罗恩，拜托！ 你妈妈说早饭已经准备好了！
- Ron, where are we actually going? - Don't know.
- 罗恩，咱们这是要去哪？ - 不知道
- Hey, Dad. Where are we going? - Haven't the foggiest.
- 嘿，老爸，我们这是去哪？ - 我也是云里雾里
Keep up!
跟上！
Arthur!
亚瑟！
It's about time, son.
你来得可真“准时”啊
Sorry, Amos. Some of us had a bit of a sleepy start.
抱歉，阿莫斯 有些人今天睡过了
This is Amos Diggory, everyone. Works with me at the Ministry.
大伙们，这是阿莫斯·迪戈里 他和我在魔法部共事
And this strapping young lad must be Cedric, am I right?
这位从天而降的年轻人肯定是 塞德里克了？
Yes, sir.
是的，先生
This way.
这边走
Merlin's beard! You must be Harry Potter.
天哪！你一定是哈利·波特
- Yes, sir. - Great, great pleasure.
- 是的，先生 - 非常，非常荣幸
Pleasure to meet you too, sir.
我也是，先生
Yes, it's just over there.
就在那
- Shall we? - Oh, yeah.
- 开始吧？ - 好唉
We don't want to be late.
我们可不想迟到
Come on. Nearly there now. Get yourself into a good position.
快点，该出发了，找好位置
Why are they all standing around that manky old boot?
他们怎么都围着那个破靴子？
- That isn't just any manky old boot. - It's a Portkey.
- 那可不是个普通的靴子 - 它是“港口钥”
Time to go!
该出发了！
What's a Portkey?
什么是“港口钥”？
- Ready! After three. One, two... - Harry!
- 准备好了么？一，二... - 哈利！
...three!
...三！
Let go, kids!
孩子们，放手！
- What?! - Let go!
- 什么？！ - 放手！
I'll bet that cleared your sinuses, eh?
你们肯定七荤八素了吧？
- Total shambles, as per usual. - Thanks.
- 和以往一样，一团糟 - 谢谢
Go on, look at that!
瞧那边！
Well, kids, welcome to the Quidditch World Cup!
孩子们，欢迎来到魁地奇世界杯！
Stay together! Keep up, girls!
别走散了，跟上，姑娘们！
Look!
看！
Come on! Keep up, girls!
快跟上，姑娘们！
Blimey!
啊呀！
Parting of the ways, I think, old chap.
老伙计，我们该分道扬镳了 比赛时见
- See you at the match. - See you.
- 比赛时见 - 到时见
- Cedric. - Ced, come on.
- 塞德里克 - 塞德里克，来啊
See you later, Cedric.
回见，塞德里克
Home sweet home.
欢迎到我们的新家
What?
什么？
- Excellent, excellent. - Ginny, look!
- 棒极了，棒极了 - 金妮，看！
- All to the bath. - Look.
- 要去厕所的速度 - 看
Girls, choose a bunk and unpack.
姑娘们，挑张床打开行李吧
Ron, get out of the kitchen. We're all hungry.
罗恩，快从厨房里出来，我们都饿着呢
- Yeah, get out of the kitchen, Ron! - Feet off the table!
- 对，罗恩，从厨房里出来！ - 把脚从桌上放下来！
- Feet off the table! - Feet off the table!
- 把脚从桌上放下来！  - 把脚从桌上放下来！
I love magic.
我爱魔法
Get your Quidditch World Cup programs here!
来这里领取魁地奇世界杯时间表！
Blimey, Dad. How far up are we?
老爸，有没有搞错 我们还要朝上走多久？
Well, put it this way:
好吧，我们这样比喻一下
If it rains...
如果下雨...
...you'll be the first to know.
...你们肯定最先知道
Father and I are in the minister's box...
爸爸和我坐部长包厢
...by personal invitation of Cornelius Fudge himself.
是康奈利·福吉亲自邀请我们来的
Don't boast, Draco.
别吹了，德拉科
There's no need with these people.
和这些人不值
Do enjoy yourself, won't you?
会玩得开心的，不是吗？
While you can.
趁自己还有口气
Come on up. Take your seats. I told you these seats would be worth waiting for.
快来，坐这边 早告诉你们这些位子值得等的了
Come on!
快来！
It's the lrish! There's Troy!
是爱尔兰队，那是特洛伊！
- And Mullet! - And Moran!
- 还有米兰！ - 还有姆勒！
Ireland! Ireland! Ireland!
爱尔兰！爱尔兰！爱尔兰！
- Here come the Bulgarians! - Yes!
- 现在出场的是保加利亚队！ - 是啊！
Who's that?
那是？
That, sis, is the best Seeker in the world.
世界上最出色的找球手
Krum! Krum! Krum!
克鲁姆！克鲁姆！克鲁姆！
Krum!
克鲁姆！
Yes!
好耶！
Good evening!
晚上好！
As Minister for Magic...
作为魔法部部长...
...it gives me great pleasure...
...我很荣幸的...
...to welcome each and every one of you...
...欢迎各位...
...to the final of the 422nd Quidditch World Cup!
...来观看第422届魁地奇世界杯的决赛！
Let the match...
比赛现在...
...begin!
...开始！
Krum! Krum! Krum!
克鲁姆！克鲁姆！克鲁姆！
There's no one like Krum.
没人能比上克鲁姆
- Krum? - Dumb Krum?
- 克鲁姆？ - 冷面克鲁姆？
He's like a bird, the way he rides the wind.
他就像一只鸟一样在空中飞行
- He's more than an athlete. - Dumb Krum.
- 他不仅仅是个运动员 - 冷面克鲁姆
He's an artist.
还是个艺术家
- I think you're in love, Ron. - Shut up.
- 我想你爱上他了，罗恩 - 胡说
Viktor, I love you
威克多尔，我爱你
Viktor, I do
威克多尔，我确实爱你
When we're apart My heart beats only for you
当你离开的时候，我的心只为你跳动
Sounds like the lrish have got their pride on.
听起来像是爱尔兰人在庆祝
Stop! Stop it!
停，停下来！
It's not the lrish.
不是爱尔兰人
We've gotta get out of here. Now!
我们得赶快离开这！ 就是现在！
Get out, it's the Death Eaters!
快跑啊，食死徒来了！
Get back to the Portkey, everybody, and stick together!
到“港口钥”那里 别走散了！
Fred, George! Ginny is your responsibility.
弗雷德，乔治，金妮由你们来照顾
Go!
快去！
Harry!
哈利！
- Keep up, you lot! - Harry!
- 大家快跟上！ - 哈利！
Harry! Harry!
哈利！ 哈利！
Morsmordre!
[咒语]
Harry!
哈利！
- Where are you? - Harry!
- 你在哪？ - 哈利！
We've been looking for you for ages!
我们找你好久了！
Thought we lost you, mate.
还以为把你给丢了
What is that?
那是什么？
Stupefy!
昏昏倒地！
Stop!
停手！
That's my son!
是我儿子！
- Ron, Harry, Hermione, you all right? - We came back for Harry.
- 罗恩，哈利，赫敏，你们没事吧？ - 我们是回来找哈利的
Which of you conjured it?
这是你们中的谁施的魔法？
- Crouch, you can't possi... - Do not lie!
- 克劳奇，你不会... - 不要撒谎！
You've been discovered at the scene of the crime.
你们在犯罪现场被发现
- Crime? - Barty! They're just kids.
- 犯罪？ - 巴蒂，他们只是孩子
What crime?
什么罪？
It's the Dark Mark, Harry. It's his mark.
哈利，这是黑魔标记，是“他”的标记
What, Voldemort?
难道是伏地魔？
Those people tonight, in the masks, they're his too, aren't they?
今天晚上那些戴着面具的人 是他的人吗？
- His followers? - Yeah.
- 他的追随者？ - 没错
Death Eaters.
食死徒
- Follow me. - There was a man, before.
- 跟我来 - 还有另外一个人，就刚才
There!
那边！
All of you, this way!
都和我到这边来！
A man, Harry?
一个人？哈利？
Who?
什么人？
I don't know.
不知道
I didn't see his face.
我没看见他的脸
Anything from the trolley?
卖糖果咯？
Anything from the trolley, dears?
亲爱的，要什么糖果么？
Packet of Drooble's...
一包糖和...
...and a Licorice Wand.
...一根甘草棒
On second thought, just the Drooble's.
我改主意了，只要糖就好
- It's all right, I'll get it. Don't worry. - Just the Drooble's. Thanks.
- 没关系，我帮你给钱 - 只要糖，谢谢
Two Pumpkin Pasties, please.
两个南瓜甜饼
Thank you.
谢谢
Anything sweet for you, dear?
亲爱的，要吃糖么？
Oh, no, I'm not hungry. Thank you.
哦，不，我不饿，谢谢
Anything from the trolley?
卖糖果咯？
This is horrible.
真糟糕
How can the Ministry not know who conjured it?
魔法部怎么会不知道这是谁干的？
Wasn't there any security or...
难道没有保安？
Loads, according to Dad.
据老爸讲很多
That's what worried them so much. Happened right under their noses.
这事就在他们眼皮底下发生 所以他们才这么担心
It's hurting again, isn't it? Your scar.
你的疤又疼了，是么？
I'm fine.
我没事
You know Sirius will want to hear about this...
小天狼星肯定想知道...
...what you saw at the World Cup and the dream.
...世界杯上发生的事还有你的梦
(小天狼星布莱克收)
Hedwig. There we go.
海德薇，去吧
Clear the runway!
跑道畅通！
Well, there's something you don't see every day.
哇，这可不是天天都能看见的
Well, now we're all settled in and sorted, I'd like to make an announcement.
现在我们都坐下了 我想宣布一件事
This castle will not only be your home this year...
这座城堡今年将不仅仅是你们的家...
...but home to some very special guests as well.
...也会是一些特殊客人的家
You see, Hogwarts has been chosen...
霍格沃茨被选中...
Yes, what is it?
什么事？
What is it?
到底怎么了？
Tell them to wait. Tell them to wait. Wait.
让他们等等，稍等
So Hogwarts has been chosen to host a legendary event:
霍格沃茨被选中来举办一项传奇性的活动
The Triwizard Tournament.
“三强争霸赛”
- For those of you who do not know... - Brilliant.
- 有人可能不清楚 - 太棒了
...the Triwizard Tournament brings together three schools...
...三强争霸赛 是一个由三所学校参加的...
...for a series of magical contests.
...系列魔法竞赛
From each school, a single student is selected to compete.
每个学校派出一名学生参赛
Now let me be clear.
特别注意的是
If chosen, you stand alone.
若被选出就要靠你自己了
And trust me when I say...
我说你们可别不信...
...these contests are not for the faint-hearted.
...胆小的人不宜参赛
But more of that later. For now, please join me in welcoming...
详情我们等会再说 现在请和我一起欢迎...
...the lovely ladies of the Beauxbatons Academy of Magic...
...布斯巴顿魔法学院可爱的女士们...
...and their headmistress, Madame Maxime.
..和她们的女校长，马克西姆夫人
Bloody hell.
老天爷
Blimey. That's one big woman.
罗恩，这女人块头真大
And now our friends from the north.
现在欢迎来自北方的朋友
Please greet the proud sons of Durmstrang...
德姆斯特朗的骄子...
...and their high master, lgor Karkaroff.
...及他们的校长，伊戈尔·卡卡洛夫
Oh, it's Krum!
噢，克鲁姆！
Blimey, it's him!
老天，是他！
Viktor Krum!
威克多尔·克鲁姆！
Albus.
阿不思
Igor.
伊戈尔
Professor Dumbly-dorr, my horses have traveled a long way.
邓不利多教授，我的马长途跋涉
- They will need attending to. - Don't worry, Madame Maxime.
- 它们也需要人照料 - 别担心，马克西姆夫人
Our gamekeeper, Hagrid, is more than capable of seeing to them.
我们的护院，海格 绝对有能力照顾它们
But you know, Monsieur Hagrid...
但海格先生，要知道...
...they drink only single-malt whiskey.
...它们只喝麦芽威士忌
You idiot!
笨蛋！
Your attention, please!
请注意！
I'd like to say a few words.
我想说几句
Eternal glory.
三强争霸赛的胜者
That is what awaits the student who wins the Triwizard Tournament.
将得到永恒的荣耀
But to do this, that student must survive three tasks.
但为达此目标，他必须经过三项考验
Three extremely dangerous tasks.
三项非常严峻的考验
- Wicked. - Wicked.
- 帅啊 - 帅啊
For this reason, the Ministry has seen fit to impose a new rule.
有鉴于此，部长决定实施一个新规则
To explain all this...
有请巴蒂·克劳奇先生...
...we have the head of the Department of lnternational Magical Cooperation...
...国际魔法合作协会会长...
...Mr. Bartemius Crouch.
...为我们解释一下
Bloody hell. It's Mad-Eye Moody.
真要命，是疯眼汉穆迪
- Alastor Moody? The Auror? - Auror?
- 阿拉斯特·穆迪，是个傲罗 - 傲罗？
Dark-wizard catcher. Half the cells in Azkaban are filled thanks to him.
捉拿黑巫师的人 阿兹卡班监狱里一半的人都是他抓的
He's supposed to be mad as a hatter, though, these days.
他最近有点神志不清了
- My dear old friend, thanks for coming. - Stupid ceiling.
- 老朋友，谢谢你能来 - 这天花板真傻气
Thank you.
谢谢
What's that he's drinking, do you suppose?
你们猜他喝的是什么？
I don't know, but I don't think it's pumpkin juice.
不知道，但肯定不是南瓜汁
After due consideration...
经过充分考虑...
...the Ministry has concluded that, for their own safety...
...魔法部决定 为了学生的安全...
...no student under the age of 17...
...17岁以下的学生...
...shall be allowed to put forth their name for the Triwizard Tournament.
...一律不许参加三强争霸赛
- This decision is final. - That's rubbish!
- 这是最终的决定 - 垃圾
That's rubbish! You don't know what you're doing!
垃圾，废话！ 你脑子是不是有病！
Silence!
安静！
The Goblet of Fire.
火焰杯
Anyone wishing to submit themselves to the tournament...
想报名参赛的人...
...need only write their name upon a piece of parchment...
...必须将自己的名字写在羊皮纸上...
...and throw it in the flame before this hour on Thursday night.
...于周四晚此时以前丢到火焰里去
Do not do so lightly.
这不是闹着玩的
If chosen, there's no turning back.
如果被选上就不能回头了
As from this moment, the Triwizard Tournament has begun.
三强争霸赛从此时开始
Alastor Moody.
我叫阿拉斯特·穆迪
Ex-Auror...
前傲罗...
...Ministry malcontent...
...对魔法部不满的人...
...and your new Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher.
...黑魔法防御课的新老师
I am here because Dumbledore asked me. End of story, goodbye, the end.
是邓不利多请我来任教的 废话到此为止
Any questions?
有什么问题么？
When it comes to the Dark Arts...
对黑魔法的教学...
...I believe in a practical approach.
...我认为实践最重要
But first, which of you can tell me how many Unforgivable Curses there are?
但首先，谁能告诉我 有多少种不可饶恕咒？
- Three, sir. - And they are so named?
- 三种，先生 - 为什么这么称呼？
Because they are unforgivable. The use of any one of them will...
是因为它们不可饶恕 使用其中任何一个
Will earn you a one-way ticket to Azkaban, correct.
都会让你拿到一张去阿兹卡班的单程票 说得没错
The Ministry says you're too young to see what these curses do.
部长说你们还太小 不适合看这些咒语的功力
I say different! You need to know what you're up against!
我不这么看 你们该知道自己要面对的是什么！
You need to be prepared.
该有所准备
You need to find another place to put your chewing gum...
菲尼根先生，你该找个...
...besides the underside of your desk, Mr. Finnigan!
...课桌下面以外的地方来扔口香糖！
No way. The old codger can see out the back of his head.
怎么回事？ 这老家伙背后长眼了
And hear across classrooms!
还有顺风耳呢！
So which curse shall we see first?
那么...我们应该先说哪一个？
- Weasley! - Yes?
- 韦斯莱 - 是的
Stand.
起立
Give us a curse.
和我们说一个
Well, my dad did tell me about one.
我爸告诉过我一个
The lmperius Curse.
迷心咒
Oh, yeah, your father would know all about that.
噢，当然，你爸爸一定很熟悉这个
Gave the Ministry quite a bit of grief a few years ago.
几年前曾经给魔法部造成不小的麻烦
Perhaps this will show you why.
让我来告诉你为什么
Hello.
你好
Lovely little beauty.
小美人
Engorgio.
[咒语]
Imperio!
迷心咒！
Don't worry. It's completely harmless.
不用担心，它不会伤害你的
If she bites...
如果它咬你一口...
...she's lethal.
...可是致命的哦
What are you laughing at?
笑什么笑？
Get off!
下去！
Talented, isn't she?
真是个天才？
What should I have her do next? Jump out the window?
接下来要做什么？ 把它扔到窗上？
Drown herself?
淹死它？
Scores of witches and wizards have claimed...
很多男女巫师...
...that they only did You-Know-Who's bidding...
...都声称自己为“那个人”做事...
...under the influence of the lmperius Curse.
...是受了迷心咒的影响
But here's the rub:
但关键是
How do we sort out the liars?
怎么判断谁在说谎？
Another, another.
再说一个
Up, up. Come on.
起来，快点
Longbottom, is it?
你是伦伯特，对么？
Up.
起立
Professor Sprout tells me you have an aptitude for herbology.
斯普劳特教授说你在草药学方面有特长
There's the...
还有...
The Cruciatus Curse.
钻心咒
Correct, correct. Come, come.
没错，没错，来，过来
Particularly nasty.
小心点
The torture curse.
折磨人的咒语
Crucio!
钻心咒！
Stop it! Can't you see it's bothering him? Stop it!
住手！没看到他很难受吗 住手！
Perhaps you could give us the last Unforgivable Curse, Miss Granger.
格兰杰小姐，能否告诉我们 最后一个咒语是什么
No?
不？
Avada Kedavra!
[咒语]
The Killing Curse.
死咒
Only one person is known to have survived it...
只有一个人曾经幸免一死...
...and he's sitting in this room.
...他就坐在这间教室里
Brilliant, isn't he?
他是个天才
Completely demented, of course, and terrifying to be in the same room with...
当然，也是个神经病 和他同处一室真可怕
...but he's really been there, you know? He's looked evil in the eye.
你知道，他曾经身临其境 曾经直面邪恶
There's a reason those curses are unforgivable.
那些咒语不可饶恕是有原因的
To perform them in a classroom... I mean, did you see Neville's face?
现在却在教室里被演示 你们真该看看纳威的表情
Neville?
纳威？
Son?
孩子？
You all right?
你没事吧？
Come on. We'll have a cup of tea. I want to show you something.
来，一起喝杯茶 我想给你看点东西
We're gonna be late!
我们要迟了！
Come on, Cedric. Put it in!
快点，塞德里克 别磨蹭！
Eternal glory. Be brilliant, wouldn't it?
永恒的荣耀，很棒不是吗？
Three years from now, when we're old enough to be chosen.
等三年之后吧，咱们够了岁数
Yeah, rather you than me.
对，选你也别选我
Yes!
好耶！
Thank you, thank you.
谢谢
- Well, lads, we've done it. - Cooked it up just this morning.
- 我们成功了 - 今天早上新出炉的
It's not going to work.
没用的
- Oh, yeah? - And why is that, Granger?
- 哦，是的  - 格兰杰，你怎么知道的？
You see this? This is an Age Line.
看到这个了么？ 这是年龄线
Dumbledore drew it himself.
邓不利多亲自画的
So?
所以？
So a genius like Dumbledore couldn't possibly be fooled...
所以，像邓不利多那样的天才...
...by a dodge as pathetically dimwitted as an Aging Potion.
...是不可能被增龄药这样的小把戏骗过的
- But that's why it's so brilliant. - Because it's so pathetically dimwitted.
- 这才是我们聪明的地方 - 因为他想不到我们会用这馊主意
- Ready, Fred? - Ready, George.
- 准备好了么，弗雷德 - 准备好了，乔治
- Bottoms up. - Bottoms up.
- 一口闷 - 一口闷
- Yes! - Yes!
- 好唉！ - 好唉！
Yeah!
好唉！
Yes!
Ready?
准备好了吗？
- Yes! - Yes!
- 好唉！ - 好唉！
- You said! - You said!
- 是你说的 - 是你说的
- Oh, right, you want a piece of me?! - I'll tear your ears off!
- 想尝尝我的厉害？！ - 看我不把你耳朵揪下来！
- Now you're making me laugh. - Take this! Come on!
- 别让我笑了 - 接招！
Fight! Fight! Fight!
打！打！打！
We're "old school", right?
我们是“老学校”，对吧？
Yeah, but you look older!
是啊，但你看起来更老了！
Sit down. Please.
请就座
Now the moment you've all been waiting for:
此时此刻，我们已等待许久
The champion selection.
勇士选拔
The Durmstrang champion is Viktor Krum.
德姆斯特朗的勇士是威克多尔·克鲁姆
The champion for Beauxbatons...
布斯巴顿的勇士是...
...is Fleur Delacour.
...芙蓉·德拉库尔
The Hogwarts champion, Cedric Diggory!
霍格沃茨的勇士是塞德里克·迪戈里！
Excellent! We now have our three champions.
好极了 我们已经选出了三位勇士
But in the end, only one will go down in history.
但最终，只有一位能被载入史册
Only one will hoist this chalice of champions...
而他将举起冠军奖杯...
...this vessel of victory...
胜利的象征...
...the Triwizard Cup!
“三强冠军杯”！
Harry Potter.
哈利·波特
Harry Potter?
哈利·波特？
No. No.
不，不
Harry Potter!
哈利·波特！
Go on, Harry.
快去，哈利
Harry, for goodness sake.
哈利，快点啊
He's a cheat!
他作弊！
He's not even 17 yet!
他还没到17岁呢
- It's wrong, I tell you! - You French tart.
- 我抗议！- 我抗议！
- Everything is a conspiracy theory with you! - Quiet! I can't think!
- 你把什么都当作阴谋！ - 安静，让我想想！
- Everything is a conspiracy theory! - I protest.
- 全都是阴谋！ - 我抗议
- Harry. - I protest!
- 哈利 - 我抗议！
Did you put your name in the Goblet of Fire?
你把自己的名字放到火焰杯里去了么？
- No, sir. - Did you ask one of the older students...
- 没有，先生 - 那是你让高年级的学生...
- ...to do it for you? - No, sir.
- ...替你做的？ - 没有，先生
- You're absolutely sure? - Yes. Yes, sir.
- 你绝对肯定？ - 是的，先生
- But of course he is lying. - The hell he is!
- 可他显然在撒谎 - 他没有
The Goblet of Fire is an exceptionally powerful magical object.
火焰杯有非常强大的魔力
Only an exceptionally powerful Confundus Charm could have hoodwinked it.
只有超强的魔法才能胜过它
Magic way beyond the talents of a fourth year.
一个四年级的学生是 不可能掌握那种魔法的
You seem to have given this a fair bit of thought, Mad-Eye.
疯眼汉，看来你有点想法
It was once my job to think as dark wizards do, Karkaroff...
卡卡洛夫，你没忘了我当年的职责 就是揣摩黑暗巫师的想法吧...
- ...perhaps you remember. - This doesn't help, Alastor.
- ...可能你还记得 - 别这样，阿拉斯特
Leave this to you, Barty.
巴蒂，就交给你决定吧
The rules are absolute.
规则是不能改的
The Goblet of Fire constitutes a binding magical contract.
火焰杯组成了一个必须遵守的魔法契约
Mr. Potter has no choice.
波特先生没有选择
He is, as of tonight...
就今夜而言，他的确是...
...a Triwizard champion.
...三强赛的勇士
This can't go on, Albus.
不能这样下去了，阿不思
First the Dark Mark. Now this?
先是黑魔标记，然后又是这个？
What do you suggest, Minerva?
米勒娃，你想说什么？
Put an end to it.
给这些画上句号
Don't let Potter compete.
别让波特参赛
You heard Barty. The rules are clear.
你听到巴蒂说的了，规则很明确
Well, the devil with Barty and his rules.
让巴蒂和他的规则见鬼去吧
And since when did you accommodate the Ministry?
曾几何时，你开始迎合魔法部了？
Headmaster, l, too, find it difficult to believe this mere coincidence.
校长，我觉得要说这都是巧合的确难以置信
However, if we are to truly discover the meaning of these events...
但是，如果想揭开这一系列事件的谜底
...perhaps we should, for the time being...
...我们也许应该...暂时..
...Iet them unfold.
...任其发展下去
What? Do nothing?
什么？袖手旁观么？
Offer him up as bait?
把他当成诱饵？
Potter is a boy, not a piece of meat.
我的意思是，波特是个孩子 而不是一块肉
I agree. With Severus.
我同意西弗勒斯的观点
Alastor, keep an eye on Harry, will you?
阿拉斯特，能帮忙照看一下哈利么？
- I can do that. - Don't let him know, though.
- 当然 - 但别让他知道
He must be anxious enough as it is...
知道未来的磨难...
...knowing what lies ahead.
...他一定已经很紧张了
Then again, we all are.
而且我们也是一样
How did you do it?
你是怎么做到的？
Never mind. Doesn't matter. Might've let your best friend know, though.
没关系，已经不重要了 至少也该让你的铁哥们知道一下
- Let you know what? - You know bloody well what.
- 让你知道什么？ - 你心里明白得很
I didn't ask for this to happen, Ron.
罗恩，我不想事情这样的
Okay?
明白吗？
- You're being stupid. - Yeah, that's me.
- 你现在表现象个傻瓜 - 对，我就是...
Ron Weasley, Harry Potter's stupid friend.
罗恩·韦斯莱 哈利·波特的傻朋友
I didn't put my name in that cup.
我没把名字放进火焰杯
I don't want eternal glory. I just wanna be...
我对永恒的荣耀不感兴趣 我只是想...
Look, I don't know what happened tonight, and I don't know why.
听着，我对今晚发生的事毫无头绪
It just did.
事情就这么发生了
Okay?
好吗？
Piss off.
瞎扯
What a charismatic quartet.
多有魅力的四人组啊
Hello.
你们好
I'm Rita Skeeter.
我是丽塔·斯基特
I write for the Daily Prophet.
为《预言家日报》写稿的
But of course you know that, don't you? It's you we don't know.
当然，你们是知道我的了 我们不了解的是你们
You're the juicy news.
你们才是生动新闻的来源
What quirks lurk beneath those rosy cheeks?
这玫瑰色的脸颊下 隐藏了什么样的奇思怪想？
What mysteries do the muscles mask?
强壮的肌肉裹着多少秘密？
Does courage lie beneath those curls?
弯曲的卷发下面又藏着多少勇气？
In short, what makes a champion tick?
大伙们，什么才是勇士的标志？
" Me, Myself & l" want to know. Not to mention my rabid readers.
我自己就很想知道 更别提我饥渴的读者们
So who's feeling up to sharing?
那么...谁先来说说？
Shall we start with the youngest? Lovely.
该从最小的开始？ 多可爱啊
This is cozy.
这里比较清静
It's a broom cupboard.
这是扫把间
You should feel right at home, then.
那你就更有家的感觉了
Don't mind if I use a Quick-Quotes Quill, do you?
我用速记笔你不介意吧？
No.
不会
So tell me, Harry.
好吧，哈利，告诉我
Here you sit, a mere boy of 12...
你，一个年仅12岁的男孩坐在这里
I'm 14. Sorry.
是14
...about to compete against three students...
面对的是其他三位学生...
...not only vastly more emotionally mature than yourself...
...他们不仅仅在心智上比你成熟许多...
...but who have mastered spells that you wouldn't attempt...
...而且掌握了就你连...
...in your dizziest daydreams.
...做梦都不敢想的咒语
Concerned?
担心么？
I don't know. I haven't really thought about it.
我不知道，没有认真考虑过
Just ignore the quill.
别管那支笔
Then, of course, you're no ordinary boy of 12, are you?
当然，你不是一个普通的12岁男孩
- Fourteen. - Your story's legend.
- 是14 - 你有传奇般的过去
Do you think it was the trauma of your past...
你认为是自己过去的创伤...
...that made you so keen to enter such a dangerous tournament?
...导致现在你急于想参加一场 如此危险的比赛吗？
No, I didn't enter.
不，不是我要参加的
Of course you didn't.
当然不是了
Everyone loves a rebel, Harry.
有点叛逆心理大家才喜欢呢，哈利
Scratch that last.
划掉最后一句
Speaking of your parents, were they alive, how do you think they'd feel?
说到你父母 如果他们还健在，你认为他们会怎么看？
Proud? Or concerned...
是骄傲，还是...
...that your attitude shows, at best, a pathological need for attention...
...忧虑你选择了这样一个 病态的寻求关注的方法...
...at worst, a psychotic death wish?
...病态的找死心理？
Hey, my eyes aren't "glistening with the ghosts of my past."
我不过是眨下眼睛 没和你说那么多吧？
Harry, I couldn 't risk sending Hedwig.
哈利，我不能冒险让海德薇过来
Since the World Cup, the Ministry's been intercepting more and more owls...
自从世界杯以后 魔法部拦截了越来越多的猫头鹰...
...and she 's too easily recognized.
...她太容易被认出了
We need to talk, Harry, face-to-face.
我们需要谈谈，哈利 面对面
Meet me in the Gryffindor common room, 1:00 this Saturday night.
周六晚一点和我在格兰芬多公休室见
And make sure you 're alone.
确保你是一个人
Sirius.
小天狼星
P.S.
另外
The bird bites.
这只鸟会咬人
Sirius?
小天狼星？
Harry Potter, age 12...
哈利·波特，12岁...
...suspect entrant in the Triwizard Tournament.
...三强争霸赛的神秘参赛者
His eyes swimming with the ghosts of his past...
他的眼中散发幽灵般往事的阴影...
...and choking back tears...
...含着泪花...
Sirius. How?
小天狼星，你怎么？
I don ' t have much time, so let me get straight to it.
我的时间不多，哈利 让我直入主题
Did you or did you not put your name into the Goblet of Fire?
你有没有把你的名字放进火焰杯里？
No!
没有！
I had to ask.
这是我必须问的
Now, tell me about this dream of yours. You mentioned Wormtail and Voldemort.
现在和我讲讲你的梦 你提到了虫尾巴和伏地魔
But who was the third man in the room?
但房间里第三个人是谁？
- I don't know. - You didn't hear a name?
- 不知道 - 你没听到他的名字？
No.
没有
Voldemort was giving him a job to do. Something important.
伏地魔给他一个任务 很重要的任务
And what was that?
什么？
He wanted...
他要...
...me.
...抓我
I don't know why. But he was gonna use this man to get to me.
我不明白，但他会利用这个人来抓我
But, I mean, it was only a dream, right?
我想这可能只是个梦而已
Yes.
对
It's just a dream.
只是个梦
Look, Harry.
听着，哈利
The Death Eaters at the World Cup, your name rising from that goblet...
世界杯时食死徒的出现 你的名字出现在火焰杯里...
...these are not just coincidences. Hogwarts isn't safe anymore.
...都不是巧合 霍格沃茨不再安全了
What are you saying?
你的意思是？
I'm saying the devils are inside the walls. Igor Karkaroff?
我是说恶魔就在你身边 伊戈尔·卡卡洛夫
He was a Death Eater. And no one, no one stops being a Death Eater.
他曾经是食死徒 食死徒魔性难改
Then there's Barty Crouch. Heart of stone. Sent his own son to Azkaban.
巴蒂·克劳奇，一个铁石心肠的人. 他把自己儿子送去了阿兹卡班
You think one of them put my name in the goblet?
是他们其中的一个把我的名字放进去的？
I haven't a clue who put your name in that goblet...
我不知道，哈利...
...but whoever did is no friend to you. People die in this tournament.
...但不管是谁，他一定不是你的朋友 争霸赛里会出人命的
- I'm not ready for this, Sirius. - You don't have a choice.
- 小天狼星，我还没有做好准备 - 你没得选择
- Someone's coming. - Keep your friends close, Harry.
- 有人来了 - 哈利，和你的朋友搞好关系
Who were you talking to?
你在和谁说话？
- What? Who says I was talking to anyone? - I heard voices.
- 什么？屋子里又没人 - 我听见声音了
Maybe you're imagining things. Wouldn't be the first time.
可能你又开始胡想了 这也不是第一次了
You're probably just practicing for your next interview, I expect.
可能是你在准备下一次的访谈吧
(幼年惨剧)
Amazing.
太奇妙了
- Amazing! - Neville. You're doing it again.
- 太奇妙了 - 纳威，你又来了
Right, sorry.
哦，抱歉
"Magical Water Plants of the Highland Lochs"?
《拉克斯高地的魔力水生物》？
Moody gave it to me. That day we had tea.
穆迪那天喝茶的时候给我的
It's already been through enough people.
反正也当着这么多人的面了
Why don't you just go and talk to him yourself?
你不如自己去说算了？
Ron, this is your problem, not mine.
罗恩，这是你自己的问题，和我无关
What do you want me to say again?
你还想让我说什么？
Go.
快去
Ronald would like me to tell you that Seamus told him...
罗恩想让我告诉你 希姆告诉他...
...that Dean was told by Parvati that Hagrid's looking for you.
...帕瓦蒂告诉蒂姆 海格在找你
Is that right? Well, you...
是么？那你...
What?
什么？
- Are you sure you won't do this? - Do it.
- 你真的要这样吗？ - 快点
Dean was told by Parvati that...
帕瓦蒂告诉蒂姆...
Please don't ask me to say it again.
别让我再说一次了
Hagrid's looking for you.
海格在找你
- Well, you can tell Ronald... - I'm not an owl!
- 你可以告诉罗纳得... - 我不是猫头鹰！
Did you bring your father's cloak, like I asked you?
带上你父亲的隐形衣了么？
Yeah, I brought the cloak. Hagrid, where are we going?
嗯，我带了 海格，我们要去哪？
You'll see soon enough.
就快到了
Now pay attention, this is important.
注意哦，这很重要
What's with the flower?
这朵花是怎么回事？
Hagrid, have you combed your hair?
海格，你居然梳了头？
As a matter of fact, I have.
我的确梳过了
You might like to try the same thing now and again.
也许以后你也应该试一试
Hagrid?
海格？
The cloak! Put the cloak on!
隐形衣，披上隐形衣！
- Bonsoir, Olympe. - Oh, Hagrid.
- 你好，奥林 - 噢，海格
I thought perhaps you weren't coming. I thought perhaps...
我以为你不会来了 我还以为...
...you had forgotten me.
...你把我给忘了
Couldn't forget you, Olympe.
怎么会呢，奥林
What is it you wanted to show me?
你想给我看什么？
When we spoke earlier, you sounded so...
我们早前谈话时，你显得那么...
...exhilarated.
...愉悦
You'll be glad you came. Trust me.
你会不虚此行的 相信我
Can we get closer?
咱们靠近些吧
Dragons?
龙？
That's the first task?
就是第一项任务？
- You're joking. - Come on, Harry.
- 开玩笑 - 别这样，哈利
These are seriously misunderstood creatures.
那是一种被严重误解的动物
Oh, crikey!
噢，好悬！
Although, I have to admit, that Horntail is a right nasty piece of work.
尽管我得承认那条匈牙利树蜂确实很凶恶
Poor Ron nearly fainted just seeing him, you know.
罗恩只是看了一下就差点昏过去
- Ron was here? - Oh, sure.
- 罗恩来过？ - 当然了
His brother Charlie helped to bring him over from Romania.
是他哥哥查理把它们从罗马尼亚带来的呢
Didn't Ron tell you that?
罗恩没告诉你？
No, he didn't.
没有
He didn't tell me a thing.
他一个字都没说
- You cheat, Potter. - You stink, Potter.
- 你作弊，波特 - 你真讨厌，波特
- Good luck, Potter. - Potter stinks!
- 祝你好运，波特 - 波特真讨厌！
- Cedric rules. - Thanks.
- 塞德里克必胜 - 谢谢
Like the badge?
喜欢我的徽章么？
Excuse me.
借过
Harry.
哈利
Hey! Read the badge, Potter!
看看徽章吧，波特！
Can I have a word?
我能和你谈谈么？
- All right. - You stink, Potter!
- 好的 - 你真差劲，波特！
- Potter, you stink! - Harry Potter smells!
- 波特，你真讨厌！ - 哈利波特真差劲！
Dragons. That's the first task.
龙是我们的第一项任务
- They've got one for each of us. - Come on, Ced!
- 每个人都有一条 - 塞德里克！
Are you serious?
你不是说笑？
And Fleur and Krum, do they...
芙蓉和克鲁姆他们知道么？
- Yes. - Come on, Ced, leave him.
- 知道 - 塞德里克，别和他罗嗦
- Right. - He's not worth it.
- 好吧 - 他不配
- Read the badges, Potter! - Hey, listen. About the badges.
- 看看徽章吧，波特！ - 听着，那个徽章
- I've asked them not to wear them, but... - Don't worry about it.
- 我叫他们不要戴... - 别担心
It's not like I try to blow things up, exactly.
不是我想它们爆炸
It just happens a fair bit.
这种事老是发生在我身上
You have to admit, though, fire's pretty fascinating.
但你得承认，那火焰很漂亮
You're a right foul git, you know that?
你真窝囊，知道么？
- You think so? - I know so.
- 是么？ - 就是
Anything else?
还有什么？
- Yeah. Stay away from me. - Fine.
- 有，离我远点 - 好
- There's Potter. Cheat. - Why so tense, Potter?
- 波特来了，他是个骗子 - 火气好大，波特
My father and I have a bet, you see.
我和父亲打了个赌
I don't think you're gonna last 10 minutes in this tournament.
我认为你在比赛里只能坚持10分钟
He disagrees. He thinks you won't last five.
他不同意 他认为只有5分钟
I don't give a damn what your father thinks, Malfoy.
我才不管你爸怎么想呢，马尔福
He's vile and cruel. And you're just pathetic.
他既卑鄙又凶残 你只是个可怜虫
- Pathetic? - Oh, no, you don't, sonny!
- 可怜虫？ - 小子，你可别这样！
I'll teach you to curse someone when their back is turned!
让我来教教你怎么在人背后下咒！
You stinking, cowardly, scummy...
你这个讨厌鬼，懦夫，渣滓...
- Professor Moody! - ...back-shooting...
- 穆迪教授！ - ...小人
- What are you doing? - Teaching.
- 你在干吗？ - 教学生
- ls that a... Is that a student? - Technically, it's a ferret.
- 那是，那是个学生么？ - 从技术上来说是只雪貂
Stand still! Stand still!
站稳了，别动！
- My father will hear about this! - ls that a threat?
- 我会告诉老爸的！ - 你在威胁我吗？
- Professor Moody! - ls that a threat?
- 教授！ - 你在威胁我吗？
Professor!
教授！
I could tell you stories about your father that would curl even your greasy hair!
你老爸的糗事我知道的可多呢！
- Alastor! Alastor. - lt doesn't end here!
- 阿拉斯特 - 走着瞧
We never use transfiguration as a punishment!
阿拉斯特，我们从不用变形魔法惩罚学生！
Surely Dumbledore told you that.
邓不利多肯定告诉过你这点吧
- He might've mentioned it. - Well, you will do well to remember it.
- 他可能提过 - 那么你这次要好好记住了
Away!
都走开！
You. Come with me.
你跟我来
That's a Foe-Glass.
那是面照妖镜
Lets me keep an eye on my enemies.
防范敌人用的
If I can see the whites of their eyes, they're standing right behind me.
如果我能看见他们的眼白 那说明他们就在我身后
Wouldn't even bother telling you what's in there.
懒得和你讲那里面是什么了
You wouldn't believe it if I did.
说了你也不信
Now...
现在...
...what are you going to do about your dragon?
...你打算怎么对付那些龙？
Well, you know, I just thought l'd...
哦...嗯...我想可能会...
Sit.
坐下
Listen to me, Potter.
听着，波特
Your pal Diggory?
你朋友迪戈里
By your age, he could turn a whistle into a watch and have it sing you the time.
在你这么大的时候 就能把口哨变成一快会报时的表
Miss Delacour?
德拉库尔小姐
She's as much a fairy princess as I am.
简直就是神话中的公主
As for Krum, his head may be filled with sawdust...
至于克鲁姆，他可能头脑简单...
...but Karkaroff's is not.
...但卡卡洛夫不是
They'll have a strategy.
他们是有备而来的
And you can bet that it will play to Krum's strengths.
会利用克鲁姆的优势
Come on, Potter.
那么，波特
What are your strengths?
你有什么优势？
I don't know.
我不知道
Well, I can fly. I mean, I'm a fair flyer. But l...
嗯，我会飞，飞得很快，但是...
- Better than fair, the way I heard it. - But I'm not allowed a broom.
- 我听说了，可不是一般得好 - 但不许用扫把啊
You're allowed a wand.
你可以用...魔杖
Bets! Place your bets!
下注了！
Bets taken! Bets taken here!
下注了！来这赌一把！
Step up, folks! Who fancies a flutter in today's bloodbath?
大家都来下注吧，出小钱赢大钱
Smart money's on Krum to survive! Any bets?
明智就投克鲁姆！还有谁要下？
Yes, sir?
您呢？
Ten-to-1 for Fleur. There you go. Thank you very much.
10比1赌芙蓉赢，拿好了 非常感谢
Your attention, please.
请注意
This is a great day for all of us.
今天对大家来说是伟大的一天
Each of the three tasks involves very considerable danger.
每项任务都很危险
Please keep your seats at all times.
比赛中请不要离开自己的座位
This will minimize any risks you may be exposed to.
这会降低你的风险
- Harry? Is that you? - Yeah.
- 哈利，是你么？ - 是的
I'm sure we all wish our champions...
我相信我们都希望勇士们...
- How are you feeling? Okay? - ... the greatest of luck.
- 你觉得怎样？还好么？ - ...有好的运气
The key is to concentrate. After that, you just have to...
关键要集中精神 此后，你只需要...
Battle a dragon.
斗龙
Young love.
年轻的爱情
How...
多么...
...stirring.
...让人激动啊
If everything goes unfortunately today...
今天如果有什么不幸...
...you two may even make the front page.
...你们俩还可以上头版呢
You have no business here.
关你什么事
This tent is for champions...
这座帐篷是给勇士...
...and friends.
...及亲友专用的
No matter. We've got what we wanted.
无所谓，我们已经得到想要的了
Good day, champions. Gather round, please.
你们好，勇士们 请靠过来
Now, you've waited, you've wondered, and at last the moment has arrived.
现在，你们期待的一刻终于到来了
A moment only four of you can fully appreciate.
只有你们四个才能体会的时刻
What are you doing here, Miss Granger?
格兰杰小姐，你在这干吗？
Sorry, I'll just go.
抱歉，我就走
Barty, the bag.
巴蒂，袋子
Champions, in a circle around me.
勇士们，围着我站成一圈
Miss Delacour, over here. Mr. Krum.
德拉库尔小姐，到这里 克鲁姆先生
And, Potter, Mr. Potter, over here. That's right. Now...
波特...波特先生，到这里 好，现在
...Miss Delacour, if you will.
...德拉库尔小姐，请
The Welsh Green.
威尔士绿龙
Mr. Krum.
克鲁姆先生
The Chinese Fireball.
中国火球龙
The Swedish Short-Snout.
瑞典短鼻龙
- Which leaves... - The Horntail.
- 剩下的就是... - 树蜂龙
- What's that, boy? - Nothing.
- 怎么了，孩子？ - 没什么
The Hungarian Horntail.
匈牙利树蜂龙
These represent four very real dragons...
这些代表了四头实实在在的龙...
...each of which has been given a golden egg to protect.
...每只守护着一个金蛋
Your objective is simple:
你们的目标很简单
Collect the egg.
拿到金蛋
This you must do, for each egg contains a clue...
这你们必须做到 因为每个蛋都有一个线索...
...without which you cannot hope to proceed to the next task.
...没有线索便无法进行下一任务
Any questions?
有什么问题么？
Very well. Good luck, champions.
很好，好运，勇士们
Mr. Diggory, at the sound of the cannon, you may...
迪戈里先生，大炮一响，你就...
Diggory! Diggory! Diggory!
迪戈里！迪戈里！迪戈里！
Three of our champions have now faced their dragons...
三位勇士已经斗败了龙...
...and so each one of them will proceed to the next task.
...他们也将继续下一任务
And now our fourth and final contestant.
现在，欢迎第四位也是最后一位参赛者
Harry! Harry! Harry!
哈利！哈利！哈利！
Your wand, Harry! Your wand!
用魔杖，哈利，用魔杖
Accio Firebolt!
[咒语]
- Yeah! - Yes!
- 好耶！ - 好！
Oh, my God.
噢，老天
- Yeah! - Yeah! Well done, dragon!
- 好啊！ - 龙，干得好！
Yes! Yes!
好！ 好！
- Yes, Harry! - Knew you wouldn't die, Harry. Lose a leg.
- 好样的，哈利 - 就知道你死不了，可能会断条腿
- Or an arm. - Pack it in altogether?
- 或者少条胳膊 - 但要你死？
- Never! - Never!
- 没门！ - 没门！
Shush!
安静！
Go on, Harry. What's the clue?
哈利，快看看 线索是什么？
- Who wants me to open it? - Yes!
- 要我打开么？ - 要
- Do you want me to open it? - Yes!
- 你们要我打开么？ - 要
What the bloody hell was that?
什么鬼东西？
All right, everyone! Go back to your knitting.
好了，大伙 回去做自己的事吧
This is gonna be uncomfortable enough without all you nosy sods listening in.
肯定很让人尴尬了 就算不让你们听那噪音
I reckon you have to be barking mad to put your own name in the Goblet of Fire.
我现在了解你一定是疯了才会 把名字放到火焰杯里去
Caught on, have you? Took you long enough.
你现在想清楚了？ 这么长时间
I wasn't the only one who thought you'd done it.
不只是我一个人这么想的
Everyone was saying it behind your back.
大家都是这么想的
Brilliant. That makes me feel loads better.
好极了 这让我感到“好过”多了
- Least I warned you about the dragons. - Hagrid warned me about the dragons.
- 至少，龙的事情是我给你报的信 - 是海格告诉我的呀
No, no, no, I did.
不，是我
No, don't you remember? I told Hermione to tell you...
你难道不记得 我叫赫敏告诉你...
...that Seamus told me that Parvati told Dean that Hagrid was looking for you.
...希姆告诉我说帕瓦蒂和蒂姆说 海格在找你
Seamus never actually told me anything, so it was really me all along.
希姆没告诉我任何事 其实都只是我
I thought we'd be all right, you know...
我以为你想明白了...
...after you'd figured that out.
...咱们之间就没事了
Who... Who could possibly figure that out?
谁能想明白啊？
That's completely mental.
完全逻辑混乱
Yeah. Isn't it?
谁说不是呢
I suppose I was a bit distraught.
我想我当时是太着急了
Boys.
男孩们毛病真多
- Hi, Harry. - Hi, Harry.
- 你好，哈利 - 你好，哈利
Cho, Harry's looking at you.
秋，哈利在看你呢
Shush.
别出声
Look at this!
瞧这个！
I can't believe it! She's done it again.
我简直不敢相信她又故技重施
"Miss Granger, a plain but ambitious girl...
格兰杰小姐 一位平凡却又野心勃勃的女孩...
...seems to be developing a taste for famous wizards.
...似乎开始钟情于著名的巫师
Her latest prey, sources report...
据悉，她最新的猎物是...
...is none other than the Bulgarian bonbon, Viktor Krum.
...保加利亚猛男威克多尔·克鲁姆
No word yet on how Harry Potter's taking this latest emotional blow."
对于哈利·波特如何看待此事 目前仍没有消息
Parcel for you, Mr. Weasley.
韦斯莱先生，你的包裹
Thank you, Nigel.
谢谢，耐吉尔
Not now, Nigel. Later.
现在不行，耐吉尔 等会
Go on.
快走
I told him I'd get him Harry's autograph.
我许诺要给他哈利的签名的
Oh, look, Mum's sent me something.
瞧，我妈给我寄的
Mum sent me a dress.
是条裙子
Well, it does match your eyes. Is there a bonnet?
和你的眼睛很配 还有女帽么？
Nose down, Harry.
放下，哈利
- Ginny, these must be for you. - I'm not wearing that, it's ghastly.
- 金妮，这肯定是给你的 - 我才不穿呢，真让人恶心
What are you on about?
你笑什么？
They're not for Ginny.
不是给金妮的
They're for you.
是给你的
- Dress robes. - Dress robes? For what?
- 礼袍 - 礼袍，干嘛用的？
The Yule Ball...
圣诞舞会...
...has been a tradition of the Triwizard Tournament...
...是三强赛的传统项目...
...since its inception.
...从首届就开始
On Christmas Eve night, we and our guests...
在平安夜，我们的客人和我们...
...gather in the Great Hall...
...将会在大厅...
...for a night of well-mannered frivolity.
...举行一场礼仪庄重的晚会
As representatives of the host school...
作为主办方学校的代表...
...I expect each and every one of you to put your best foot forward.
...我希望你们每个人拿出最好的姿态
And I mean this literally, because...
我可是认真的，因为...
...the Yule Ball is, first and foremost...
...圣诞晚会首先是一个...
...a dance.
...舞会
Silence!
安静！
The house of Godric Gryffindor has commanded the respect...
戈德里克·格兰芬多学院 10个世纪以来已经赢得了...
...of the wizard world for nearly 10 centuries.
...魔法届的普遍尊重
I will not have you, in the course of a single evening, besmirching that name...
我不会让你们在一夜之间因为 表现得像...
...by behaving like a babbling, bumbling band of baboons.
...一群胡作非为的狒狒而把 这个名字玷污
Try saying that five times fast, huh?
试试说5倍快？
Now, to dance...
现在，说到跳舞...
...is to let the body breathe.
...是让身体呼吸
Inside every girl, a secret swan slumbers...
每个女孩体内, 都有一只天鹅...
...Ionging to burst forth and take flight.
...振翅欲飞
Something's about to burst out of Eloise Midgen, but I don't think it's a swan.
爱洛斯·米根身体里也要蹦出东西来了 但我想不是天鹅
Inside every boy, a lordly lion prepared to prance.
在每个男孩体内 有一只狮子准备要猎食
- Mr. Weasley. - Yes?
- 韦斯莱先生 - 是的
Will you join me, please?
你能加入我吗？
Now, place your right hand on my waist.
把你的右手放在我的腰上
- Where? - My waist.
- 放那里？ - 我的腰上
And extend your arm.
而且伸直你的骼膊
Mr. Filch, if you please.
请放音乐
One, two, three.
1，2，3
One, two, three. One, two, three.
1，2，3，1，2，3
Never gonna let him forget this, are you?
咱们得把这个故事流传下去
- Never. - Never.
- 到永远 - 到永远
Everybody come together. Boys, on your feet!
所有人都来加入我们 男孩们，都站起来！
Why do they have to travel in packs?
她们为什么总是聚在一起
How are you supposed to get one on their own to ask them?
我怎么才能和其中的一个说话？
Blimey, Harry. You've slayed dragons. If you can't get a date, who can?
管它，哈利，你和龙战斗过 若连你都找不到舞伴，还能有谁可以？
I think I'd take the dragon right now.
我想这比斗龙也容易不到哪去
I take after my mum.
我长的像我妈
Though I didn't know her very well. She left when I was about 3.
我对她了解不多 我3岁时，她就离开了我们
No, not the maternal sort, her.
我不是那么伤心
Broke me dad's heart, though. He was a tiny little fella, my dad.
但是我父亲却伤心透了 我父亲是个小个子
I could pick him up at the age of 6 with one hand and put him up on the dresser.
我在6岁时就可以轻松举起 我的父亲，然后把他放到衣橱里
He laughed so hard at that.
他总为这个笑的很厉害
Very funny.
非常有趣
And then he died just when I started school, so...
而他在我上学的时候也去世了...
So I sort of had to make me own way, as it were.
所以我要自己照顾自己
But enough of me. What about you?
不要说我了 说说关于你的事
This is mad. At this rate, we'll be the only ones in our year without dates.
这真是太疯狂了 也许只有我们没有舞伴了
Well, us and Neville.
纳威也没有
Yeah, but, then again, he can take himself.
他至少可以带自己去
It might interest you to know that Neville's already got someone.
我听说他已经找到舞伴了
Now I'm really depressed.
现在我真的很郁闷
"Get a move on or all the good ones will have gone."
快找一个好舞伴 不然都被别人抢走了
Who you going with, then?
你和谁去？
- Oi, Angelina? - What?
- 安吉莉娜？ - 什么？
Do you wanna go to the ball with me?
你...想和我一起参加舞会吗？
To the ball?
舞会？
Yeah, all right.
好的
Oi, Hermione.
赫敏
You're a girl.
你也是个女的啊
Very well spotted.
你终于注意到了
Come with one of us?
你可以选择我们其中一个
Come on. It's one thing for a bloke to show up alone.
算了吧，男孩单身还过得去
For a girl, it's just sad.
但是你个女孩子，太惨无人睹了
I won't be going alone, because, believe it or not, someone's asked me!
我不会单身去的 不管你信不信，已经有人邀请我了
And I said yes!
而且我也答应了
Bloody hell.
活见鬼
She's lying, right?
她吹牛
If you say so.
随你怎么说
Look, we've just gotta grit our teeth and do it.
不管怎样我们也得找个人跟我们去
Tonight, when we get back to the common room, we'll both have partners. Agreed?
明天回休息室之时 都要带上自己得舞伴，同意？
Agreed.
同意
- Cho! - Harry!
- 秋 - 哈利
Watch yourself on the stairs. It's a bit icy at the top.
当心楼梯，上面比较滑
Okay, thanks.
谢谢
Cho?
秋？
Yes?
怎么？
Well, I just wondered if you...
我想...你能不能...
I wondered if maybe you wanted to go to the ball with me.
我想你能不能做我舞伴？
Sorry, I didn't catch that.
什么，我没听清楚
I was just wondering if maybe you wanted to go to the ball with me.
我可以邀请你做我的舞伴吗
Harry...
哈利...
...I'm sorry, but someone's already asked me.
...对不起 已经有人邀请我了
And...
而且...
Well, I've said I'll go with him.
我也答应他了
Okay. Yeah. Great.
那也好，没事，挺好的
Fine. No problem.
没关系的，没问题
Okay. Good.
好的
Harry?
哈利？
I really am...
我真的...
...sorry.
...很抱歉
It's all right, Ron.
没关系的，罗恩
It's okay, Ron. It's all right. It doesn't matter.
罗恩，真的没事，无所谓
What happened to you?
你怎么了？
He just asked Fleur Delacour out.
他刚才去邀请芙蓉·德拉库尔
- What? - What did she say?
- 什么？ - 她怎么说？
No, of course.
当然是不
- She said yes? - Don't be silly.
- 难道同意了？ - 别傻了
There she was, walking by. You know how I like it when they walk.
她只是刚好路过 你知道我很喜欢她走路的样子
I couldn't help it. It just sort of slipped out.
我控制不住自己 话就从嘴里溜了出来
Actually, he sort of screamed at her. It was a bit frightening.
实际上，他是冲她大声吼叫 很吓人
- And what did you do then? - What else? I ran for it.
- 然后你呢？ - 还能怎么样，我跑掉了
I'm not cut out for this, Harry. I don't know what got into me.
我摆脱不了这阴影了 真不知道自己怎么回事
- Hi, Harry. - Hi, Harry.
- 嗨，哈利  - 嗨，哈利
I always liked looking at them from behind.
我总是看到她们的背影
She's never gonna forgive me, ever.
我看她是永远不会原谅我的了
Hey!
喂！
Bloody hell.
真要命
Bloody...
要命...
Oh, bloody...
噢，要命...
What are those? What are those?
你穿的什么？ 你穿的什么？
- My dress robes. - Well, they're all right!
- 我的礼袍 - 嗯，它们还好吧！
No lace. No dodgy little collar.
没有花边、没有讨厌的衣领
Well, I expect yours are more traditional.
我觉得你的更传统
Traditional?! They're ancient! I look like my Great Aunt Tessie!
传统？简直是古董！ 让我看上去像婶婶泰茜
I smell like my Great Aunt Tessie.
闻着也像婶婶泰茜
Murder me, Harry.
杀了我吧，哈利
Leave it alone!
别乱想了！
Poor kid. I bet she's alone in her room, crying her eyes out.
可怜的孩子 我打赌她肯定一个人在房间里哭呢
- Who? - Hermione, of course.
- 谁？ - 当然是赫敏啦
Come on, Harry, why do you think she wouldn't tell us who she's coming with?
还不明白吗，哈利 否则她为什么不告诉我们她跟谁来？
Because we'd take the mickey out of her if she did.
因为她怕我们取笑她
Nobody asked her. Would've taken her myself if she wasn't so bloody proud.
没人邀请她 她要是不那么傲气，我就去请她了
- Hello, boys. - Hello, boys.
- 你们好 - 你们好
Don't you look...
你的衣服真是...
...dashing.
...有个性
There you are, Potter. Are you and Miss Patil ready?
总算找到你了波特 你和佩蒂尔小姐准备好了吗？
- Ready, professor? - To dance.
- 什么准备好，教授？ - 跳舞啊
It's traditional that the three champions... Well, in this case, four.
这是老规矩了，三个冠军选手 现在是四个了
...are the first to dance.
...最先入场跳舞
- Surely I told you that. - No.
- 相当肯定我告诉你了 - 您没有
Well, now you know.
那你现在也知道了
As for you, Mr. Weasley, you may proceed into the Great Hall with Miss Patil.
至于你，韦斯莱先生 你也可以和佩蒂尔小姐一起进礼堂了
- Oh, there you are. - Come on, then.
- 你们也来了 - 快走吧
Come along this way.
这边走
Oh, come on.
快点
- Hi. - Now, I need you all to line up...
- 嗨! - 大家排好队...
...in the procession, please. Oh, you are very late.
...你可迟到了
This way. This way. Come along.
这边走，跟上
She looks beautiful!
她真美！
Yeah, she does.
对，没错
Is that Hermione Granger? With Viktor Krum?
那是赫敏·格兰杰和威克多尔·克鲁姆吗？
No. Absolutely not.
不可能，怎么可能
Hi!
嗨！
Harry, take my waist.
哈利，挽着我的腰
- What? - Now!
- 什么？ - 快点
Are you ready?
你们准备好了吗？
Move your body like a hairy troll
摆动你们的身体
Learning to rock and roll
学着摇摆起来
Spin around like a crazy elf
像疯狂的小精灵那样转啊转
Dancing by himself
像他那样舞动
Boogie down like a unicorn
像独角兽那样摇摆
No stopping till the break of dawn
一直到黎明
Put your hands up in the air
空中舞动你的手
Like an ogre who just don 't care
就像老女人一样，什么都不管
Can you dance like a Hippogriff?
你能像飞马那样跳舞吗？
Ruddy pumpkinhead, isn't he?
不觉得他像个红色的南瓜吗？
I don't think it was the books that had him going to the library.
我觉得他就像图书馆到处乱放的书
May I have your arm?
可以邀你一起吗？
Arm. Leg. I'm yours.
手，腿，都是你的了
Hot, isn't it?
他很帅，对吗？
Viktor's gone to go and get drinks. Would you care to join us?
威克多尔去拿酒了 你们也一起来吧
No, we'd not care to join you and Viktor.
不，我们可不想打扰你跟威克多尔
What's got your wand in a knot?
你发什么神经？
He's a Durmstrang. You're fraternizing with the enemy.
他是德姆斯特朗学校的 你居然跟敌人这么亲密
The enemy? Who was it wanting his autograph?
敌人？是谁一直想要他的亲笔签名？
Besides, the whole point of the tournament...
再说，比赛的目的...
...is international magical cooperation...
...是促进国际间的魔法交流...
...to make friends.
...广交朋友
I think he's got a bit more than friendship on his mind.
我觉得他可不只是想交朋友那么简单
Are you going to ask me to dance or not?
你到底想不想和我跳舞？
No.
不
- He's using you. - How dare you?!
- 他在利用你 - 你怎么能这样说？！
- Besides, I can take care of myself. - I doubt it. He's way too old.
- 我能处理好我自己的事情 - 我倒不觉得，他对你来说太老了
- What?! What? That's what you think? - Yeah, that's what I think.
- 什么？！什么？你竟然真的这样认为？ - 没错，我就是这样想的
You know the solution then, don't you?
那你应该有好点子了？
- Go on. - Next time there's a ball...
- 继续说 - 下次再有舞会的时候...
...pluck up the courage and ask me before somebody else does!
...鼓起勇气 在别人邀请我之前邀请我！
And not as a last resort.
我可不是最后的替补
Well, that's... I mean, that's just completely off the point.
我的意思是 你完完全全偏题了
Harry.
哈利
Where have you been?
你去哪里了？
Never mind! Off to bed, both of you.
没关系！都去睡觉吧，你们两个
- They get scary when they get older. - Ron, you spoiled everything!
- 她年纪越大越可怕！ - 罗恩，你把一切都搞砸了！
What's this about?
这是什么？
No, don 't let
不，不要让
This magic die
这魔法消逝
The answer's there
答案就在那儿
Let me see it again.
让我再看一次
Yes, the time is close now.
是的，时辰就快到了
Harry, at last!
哈利，终于！
Step aside, Wormtail, so I can give our guest a proper greeting.
你让开，虫尾巴 让我来好好招待一下我们的客人
You all right, Harry?
你没事吧，哈利？
I just got in.
我刚好经过
Me.
是我啊
Harry, you told me you'd figured the egg out weeks ago.
哈利，几星期前你就说 你已经解开金蛋之谜了
- The task is two days from now. - Really? I had no idea.
- 离下个任务只有两天了 - 是吗？我也没办法
I suppose Viktor's already figured it out.
我猜威克多尔已经解出来了
Wouldn't know. We don't actually talk about the tournament.
不知道，我们从来没有 讨论过比赛的事情
Actually, we don't really talk at all. Viktor's more of a physical being.
事实上我们都不怎么说话 威克多尔更像是一个身体强健的人
I just mean he's not particularly loquacious.
我的意思是他不太唠叨
Mostly, he watches me study.
大多数时候他就看着我学习
It's a bit annoying, actually.
其实这样挺讨厌的
You are trying to figure this egg out, aren't you?
你一定会解开金蛋之谜的对吗？
What's that supposed to mean?
你到底想说什么？
It just means these tasks are designed to test you...
这个任务只是对你的一个考验...
...in the most brutal way. They're almost cruel.
用最残忍和最残酷方式
And...
况且...
...I'm scared for you.
...我都为你担惊受怕
You got by the dragons mostly on nerve.
虽然你上次勇敢地战胜了火龙
I'm not sure it's going to be enough this time.
但是这次就不一定了
Hey, Potter!
嗨，波特！
- Potter! - Cedric.
- 波特！ - 塞德里克
How... How are you?
你怎么样？
Spectacular.
精心备战中
I realize I never really thanked you properly for tipping me off about those dragons.
我其实还没有好好谢谢你 告诉我巨龙的事
Forget it. I'm sure you would've done the same for me.
没关系 如果你是我，你也会这样做的
Exactly.
你说对了
You know the Prefects' bathroom on the fifth floor?
你知道五楼的浴室吗
It's not a bad place for a bath.
那是个不错的洗澡的地方
Just take your egg...
带上你的蛋...
...and mull things over in the hot water.
...在热水里好好想想
I must be out of my mind.
我一定是疯了
I'm definitely out of my mind.
我的确是疯了
I'd try putting it in the water if I were you.
如果我是你我会把它放到水里试试
Myrtle!
桃金娘！
Hello, Harry.
你好，哈利
Long time no see.
好久不见了
I was circling a blocked drain the other day...
那天我在一处截流处玩耍的时候...
...and could swear I saw a bit of Polyjuice Potion.
...我看到了一种变身水
Not being a bad boy again, are you, Harry?
不要做坏孩子哦，哈利
Polyjuice Potion?
变身水？
Kicked the habit. Myrtle, did you say, "Try putting it in the water"?
桃金娘，你是说把它放到水里试一试吗？
That's what he did.
他就是那样做的
The other boy...
另一个男孩...
...the handsome one...
...很帅的那个...
...Cedric.
...塞德里克
Well, go on. Open it.
好了，打开它吧
Come seek us Where our voices sound
顺着歌声来寻觅我们
We cannot sing Above the ground
我们不能在陆地上歌唱
An hour long you'll have to look
你有一个小时的时间来找到我们
To recover what we took
取回我们带走的东西
Myrtle...
桃金娘...
...there aren't merpeople in the Black Lake, are there?
...黑湖里面没有人鱼是吗？
Very good.
没错
It took Cedric ages to riddle it out.
塞德里克想了好久才想出来
Almost all the bubbles were gone.
几乎所有的泡泡都没有了
Harry, tell me again.
哈利，你再说一遍
"Come seek us where our voices sound."
“顺着歌声来寻觅我们在哪里”
The Black Lake, that's obvious.
很明显是黑湖
"An hour long you'll have to look."
“一小时之内你一定要找到”
Again, obvious. Though, admittedly, potentially problematic.
还是很明显，一定是困难重重
"Potentially problematic"?
困难重重？
When's the last time you held your breath underwater for an hour, Hermione?
你什么时候在水下呆过一个小时？赫敏
Look, Harry, we can do this. The three of us can figure it out.
哈利，我们一定能想出办法 我们三个一定能想出来
Hate to break up the skull session.
这场热烈的会议该停止了
Professor McGonagall wants you in her office.
麦格教授在她办公室等你们
Not you, Potter, just Weasley and Granger.
没有你，波特 就你们两个，韦斯莱和格兰杰
But, sir, the second task is only hours away, and...
老师但是 离第二个任务只剩下几小时了
Exactly. Presumably Potter is well prepared by now...
没错，我想波特已经准备好了...
...and could do with a good night's sleep.
...该去睡个好觉了
Go. Now!
快走！立刻！
Longbottom!
隆巴顿！
Why don't you help Potter put his books back.
你帮波特收拾一下书
You know, if you're interested in plants...
如果你对植物感兴趣...
...you'd be better off with Goshawk's Guide to Herbology.
...那你应该按着 这本书的向导去学草药学
Do you know there's a wizard in Nepal who's growing gravity-resistant trees?
你知道吗在尼泊尔面有个巫师吗？ 他种出了反重心的树
Neville, no offense, but I really don't care...
纳威，恕我冒犯...
...about plants.
...我对植物一点都不敢兴趣
Now, if there's...
现在如果...
...a Tibetan turnip that will allow me to breathe underwater for an hour...
...有一种魔法芜箐 能让我在水下呼吸一小时...
...then great. But otherwise...
...那才是我真正要的，否则
I don't know about a turnip. But you could always use gillyweed.
我并不了解芜箐 但是你可以用呼吸草
- Any bets? Any bets? - Come on, place your bets!
- 快下注！ - 快下注！
Step up, mates! Don't be shy.
大家来啊，不要害羞.
- Three lads. - One lady.
- 三个男生 - 一个女生
- Four go down. - But do four come up?
- 四个都下去了 - 但都能上来吗？
Don't be so mean.
别那么低级
- Any bets? - Fleur's 10-1.
- 谁还要下注？ - 芙蓉一赔一
- You're sure about this, Neville? - Absolutely.
- 你确定这能行吗，纳威？ - 肯定行
- For an hour? - Most likely.
- 维持一个小时？ - 应该会吧
Most likely?
应该会？
Well, there is some debate among herbologists...
这得看情况...
...as to the effects of fresh water versus salt water...
...有的能活跃于淡水，有的则喜欢咸水
You're telling me this now? You must be joking!
你怎么现在才告诉我？ 开什么玩笑！
I just wanted to help.
我只是想帮你
Well, that makes you a right sight better than Ron and Hermione.
不管怎样，你的主意 比赫敏和罗恩的好多了
Where are they anyway?
他们人呢？
- You seem a little tense, Harry. - Do l?
- 你看上去有点紧张，哈利 - 是吗？
Welcome to the second task.
欢迎来到第二场比赛
Last night, something was stolen from each of our champions.
昨晚，我们从各个选手那儿 取走一样东西
A treasure of sorts.
一样财富
These four treasures, one for each champion...
每个人的财富...
...now lie on the bottom of the Black Lake.
...都被安置于黑湖之中
In order to win...
获胜的标准是...
...each champion need only find their treasure and return to the surface.
...找到你们的财富然后安全抵达湖面
- Simple enough, except for this: - Put that in your mouth.
- 有了这个就太简单了 - 把呼吸草放到你的嘴里
They will have but one hour to do so, and one hour only.
他们只能维持一小时 记住只有一小时
After that, they'll be on their own. No magic will save them.
超过一小时就没救了 魔法也救不了他们
You may begin at the sound of the cannon.
你们可以在炮声后开始
- What's the matter with him? - I don ' t know, I can ' t see him.
- 他怎么了？ - 不知道，我看不到他
Oh, my God. I've killed Harry Potter.
哦，天哪 是我害了哈利·波特
Yeah!
耶！
What?
怎么了？
The Beauxbatons champion, Miss Delacour...
布斯巴顿的选手 德拉库尔小姐...
...has unfortunately been forced to retire...
...很不幸被迫退出...
...so she will take no further part in this task.
...无法再继续接下来的比赛
But she' s my friend too!
但她也是我的朋友！
Only one!
只能救一个！
Let's get down below.
我们下去吧
Krum! Krum! Krum!
克鲁姆！克鲁姆！克鲁姆！
Yes!
好啊！
Ascendio!
[咒语]
Harry!
哈利！
He's all right.
他没事
He's all right. Barty!
他没事，巴蒂！
- Go get him another towel. - I want all the judges over here now!
- 给他拿块毛巾 - 所有的裁判过来集合！
You saved her, even though she wasn't yours to save.
你救了她，尽管你可以不用救她
My little sister.
我的妹妹
Thank you.
谢谢你
And you! You helped.
还有你，你也帮了她
Well, yeah, a bit.
恩，就那么一点点
- Harry! - Hermione!
- 哈利！ - 赫敏！
Are you all right? You must be freezing.
你没事吧？ 你一定冻坏了
Personally, I think you behaved admirably.
我非常钦佩你
I finished last, Hermione.
我是最后一名，赫敏
Next to last. Fleur never got past the Grindylows.
倒数第二 芙蓉退出了
Krum! Krum! Krum!
克鲁姆！克鲁姆！克鲁姆
- Come on! Come on! - Attention!
- 好啊！干得漂亮！ - 安静！
Attention!
注意了！
The winner is Mr. Diggory...
获胜者是迪戈里先生...
...who showed innate command of the Bubble-Head Charm.
...他使用气泡膜帮助呼吸
However, seeing as Mr. Potter would have finished first...
波特本来可以第一个上岸...
...had it not been for his determination to rescue not only Mr. Weasley...
...但是他救了韦斯莱以后...
...but the others as well, we've agreed to award him...
...还毅然决定营救他人 我们同意授予他...
...second place...
...第二名...
- Second place! - Well done!
- 第二名！ - 干得漂亮！
...for outstanding moral fiber!
...因为他舍己为人的精神！
Yes!
好啊！
- Right on. - All that moral fiber, eh?
- 是啊 - 舍己为人的精神？
- It's great. - Moral fiber?
- 太棒了 - 舍己为人？
Blimey. Even when you go wrong, it turns out right.
坏事在你手里也变成好事
- Yeah, well done, Moral Fiber. - Congratulations, Potter.
- 做的好，舍己为人的孩子 - 恭喜你波特
- A fine achievement. - Thank you.
- 战绩不错 - 谢谢
Well done, boy.
干得不错孩子
- See you at Hagrid's, Harry. - I'm sorry we haven't spoken.
- 等会在海格那儿见，哈利 - 抱歉，我们一直都没有机会谈谈
After all, your story is one I've heard so many times.
我已经听了很多遍你的故事了
Quite remarkable, really. Tragic, of course...
印象深刻，真的 当然，也很悲伤...
...to lose one's family.
...失去了家庭
Never whole again, are we?
无法再次团聚，是吗？
Still, life goes on...
但是生活还得继续...
...and here we stand.
...迎接新的一天到来
I'm sure your parents would be very proud of you today, Potter.
我敢肯定你父母一定会为你骄傲的
Bartemius!
巴蒂！
Not trying to lure Potter into one of the Ministry's summer internships, are we?
你不是想让波特夏天去你那里打工吧？
The last boy who went into the Department of Mysteries never came out!
上次你带去的那个小男孩 就一直没有回来过！
And they say I'm mad.
他们还说我是疯子！
Now, I remember... I remember when I first met you all.
我们初次见面还记忆犹新
Biggest bunch of misfits I ever set eyes on.
你是我见过的最奇怪的孩子
Suppose you remind me of meself a little.
你总是让我想到我自己
- And here we all are, four years later. - We're still a bunch of misfits.
- 四年后的我们 - 我们还是那张脸
Well, maybe, but we've all got each other.
是啊，也许吧 但我们却是好朋友
And Harry, of course.
当然，还有哈利
Soon to be the youngest Triwizard champion there's ever been!
而且很快就会成为 最年轻的三强赛冠军
Hooray!
万岁！
Hogwarts, Hogwarts Hoggy Warty Hogwarts
霍格沃茨，霍格沃茨 霍格，沃茨，霍格沃茨
Teach us something, please
教我们一些东西吧
Mr. Crouch?
克劳奇先生？
A man has died here, Fudge. And he won't be the last. You must take action.
有人死在这儿，福吉 而且他不会是最后一个，你应该采取行动
I will not.
这样不行
In times like these, the wizard world looks to its leaders for strength, Dumbledore!
在这种非常时期，巫师界希望 得到他们的领导的支持，邓不利多
Then for once show them some!
让他们自己看看！
The Triwizard Tournament will not be canceled. I will not be seen as a coward!
三强争霸赛不会被取消 我不会让别人认为我是胆小鬼！
A true leader does what is right, no matter what others think.
真正的领导人只会做正确的事 他不会管别人怎么想
- What did you say to me? - Excuse me, gentlemen.
- 你是在对我说话吗？ - 抱歉，先生
It may interest you to know this conversation is no longer private.
我们的对话已经不再是秘密了
Oh, Harry!
你好，哈利
Harry, how good to see you again.
很高兴又见到你哈利
I can come back later, professor.
我可以等会再来
Not necessary, Harry. The minister and l are done. I'll be back in a moment.
哦，没事了我跟部长已经谈好了 我等会就回来
Minister, after you.
您请，部长
There you are. Your hat.
您的帽子，先生
Oh, Harry, do feel free to indulge in a little Licorice Snap in my absence.
哈利，不用拘束，自己拿糖吃
But I have to warn you, they're a wee bit sharp.
但是我提醒你，他们很难应付
Professor?
教授？
- Professor. - Yeah.
- 教授 - 是的
Igor Karkaroff, you have been brought from Azkaban at your own request...
伊戈尔·卡卡洛夫应你要求 把你从阿兹卡班带到议会提供证据...
...to present evidence to this council.
...如果你的证词无误
Should your testimony prove consequential...
证据确凿...
...council may be prepared to order your immediate release.
...议会将考虑将你当场释放
Until such time, you remain in the eyes of the Ministry a convicted Death Eater.
但是现在，你仍是一个有罪的食死徒
Do you accept these terms?
你接受对你的条款吗？
- I do, sir. - And what do you wish to present?
- 我接受，长官 - 你有什么证据？
I have names, sir.
我有名单，长官
There was Rosier, Evan Rosier.
有一个人叫罗斯，埃文·罗斯
- Rosier is dead. - He took a piece of me with him...
- 罗斯已经死了 - 就会胡扯一些事来搬弄是非...
- ...though, didn't he? - I didn't know.
- ...不是吗？ - 我不知道
- lf that is all the witness has to offer... - No, no, no.
- 这就是你能提供的所有证据吗？ - 不，不
There was Rookwood! He was a spy.
还个人叫洛克伍德，他是一个间谍
Augustus Rookwood? Of the Department of Mysteries?
教堂部门的奥古斯·洛克伍德？
Yeah, the same.
对，就是他
He passed information to You-Know-Who from inside the Ministry itself.
他把消息发送到外面去的给“那个人”
Very well. Council will deliberate.
很好，议会会考虑的
In the meantime, you will return to Azkaban.
目前你还要被遣送回阿兹卡班
No! Wait! Wait, please! Please, I have more! What about Snape? Severus Snape?
不！不！不要！等一下，我还有 斯内普！西弗勒斯·斯内普
As the council is aware, I've given evidence on this matter.
议会应该看过我呈上的证据
Severus Snape was indeed a Death Eater and, prior to Lord Voldemort's downfall...
西弗勒斯·斯内普曾经确实是食死徒 但是他在伏地魔垮台之前...
- ...turned spy for us at great personal risk. - It's a lie!
- ...就加入了我们的行列 - 他在撒谎！
- Today he's no more a Death Eater than I am. - Snape remains faithful to the Dark Lord!
- 今天他已经不再是食死徒了 - 他还是对黑暗魔头效忠的！
Silence!
安静！
Unless the witness possesses any genuine name of consequence...
除非证人还能提供其他人的名字...
...this session is now concluded.
...否则本庭宣布结束
Oh, no, no, no.
噢，不，不，不！
I've heard about one more.
我还知道一个
- What's that? - The name.
- 什么？ - 名字
- Yes? - I know for a fact...
- 嗯？ - 我知道的...
...this person took part in the capture...
...他还参与了绑架...
...and, by means of the Cruciatus Curse...
...还用了诅咒魔法...
...torture of the Auror Frank Longbottom and his wife!
...折磨弗兰克·隆巴顿和他的妻子！
The name. Give me the wretched name!
他的名字 告诉我这个卑劣的名字
Barty Crouch...
巴蒂·克劳奇...
...Junior.
...小巴蒂·克劳奇
Hold him down!
抓住他！
Get your filthy hands off me, you pathetic little men!
放开你们的手！ 你们这些可怜的人！
Hello, Father.
你好，父亲
You are no son of mine.
你不是我儿子
Curiosity is not a sin, Harry. But you should exercise caution.
好奇不是罪过，哈利 但是你要小心谨慎
It's a Pensieve.
这是记忆盘
Very useful if, like me, you find your mind a wee bit stretched.
对我而言非常有用 当脑子里的事情杂乱无章时
It allows me to see once more things I've already seen.
你可以用它再来回顾一下 我做过的事
You see, Harry, I have searched and searched for something...
知道吗哈利，我搜索了很久...
...some small detail...
...想找一些细节...
...something I might have overlooked...
...一些我没有注意到的事...
...something that would explain why these terrible things have happened.
...一些能解开噩耗之谜的
Every time I get close to an answer, it slips away.
每次感觉就快要找到了 线索又消失了
It's maddening.
我真是心急如焚啊
Sir? Mr. Crouch's son.
老师？克劳奇的儿子
What exactly happened to him?
后来他怎么了？
He was sent to Azkaban. Destroyed Barty to do it.
被遣送到阿兹卡班去了 这对巴蒂的打击很大
But he had no choice. The evidence was overwhelming.
但是他也没有选择 证据确凿
- Why do you ask? - It's just that l...
- 你问这干嘛？ - 只是我...
I had a dream about him.
我梦见过他
It was in the summer, before school.
那是在夏天，开学以前
In the dream, I was in a house.
在梦里，我在一幢房子里
And Voldemort was there, only he wasn 't quite human.
伏地魔也在那里 只有他不是人形
And Wormtail was there too. And Mr. Crouch 's son.
虫尾巴也在那里 还有克劳奇的儿子
- Have there been others like this dream? - Yes.
- 其它的梦都跟这个一样？ - 是的
Always the same one.
总是重复做同一个
Sir, these dreams...
老师，这些梦...
...what I see, you don ' t think it' s actually happening, do you?
...我所看到的 你不认为它是在真的发生,对吗？
I think it's unwise for you to linger over these dreams, Harry.
我想你还是不要去多想这些梦了
I think it's best if you simply...
我觉得最好你...
...cast them away.
...把这些都忘了吧
It's a sign, Severus. You know what it means as well as l.
这是一个信号，西弗勒斯 你和我都知道这是什么意思
Potter!
波特！
What's your hurry?
你在干什么？
Congratulations, your performance in the Black Lake was inspiring.
恭喜你，你在黑湖里面所用的是...
Gillyweed, am I correct?
呼吸草，我说的对吗？
Yes, sir.
是的，老师
Ingenious.
真聪明
A rather rare herb, gillyweed.
很少人知道呼吸草
Not something found in your everyday garden.
那可是很难弄到的东西
Nor is this.
这个也同样
Know what it is?
你知道这是什么吗？
Bubble juice, sir?
泡泡汁，老师？
Veritaserum.
它其效无比
Three drops of this and You-Know-Who himself would spill his darkest secrets.
只要三滴就能让你 最私处的秘密暴露无遗
The use of it on a student is, regrettably, forbidden. However...
但是对学生使用它是绝对禁止的 但是...
...should you ever steal from my personal stores again...
...你要是再敢从我的 私人收藏中偷东西的话...
...my hand might just slip over your morning pumpkin juice.
...说不定我不小心就 撒一点在你的南瓜脑袋里
- I haven't stolen anything. - Don't lie to me.
- 我没偷过任何东西 - 不要跟我说谎
Gillyweed may be innocuous, but boomslang skin, lacewing flies?
呼吸草也许不是你做的 但是毒蛇皮和苍蝇翅膀呢？
You and your little friends are brewing Polyjuice Potion, and believe me...
你和你的伙伴还拿了变身水 相信我...
...I'm going to find out why!
...我一定会查出真相的
- Yeah! - Yeah!
- 好啊！ - 好！
Sonorus!
肃静！
Earlier today, Professor Moody placed the Triwizard Cup deep within the maze.
今天早时穆迪教授 把火焰杯放到了迷宫的深处
Only he knows its exact position. Now, as Mr. Diggory...
只有他才知道放到了哪里 由于迪戈里...
...and Mr. Potter...
...和波特...
...are tied for first position...
...并列第一...
...they will be the first to enter the maze, followed by Mr. Krum...
...他们将最先进入迷宫 接着是克鲁姆...
- ...and Miss Delacour. - Come on! Krum! Krum! Krum!
- 然后是德拉库尔 - 加油！克鲁姆！克鲁姆！克鲁姆！
The first person to touch the cup will be the winner!
首先拿到奖杯的选手将成为冠军！
I've instructed the staff to patrol the perimeter.
老师们会在周围巡视
Should, at any point, a contestant wish to withdraw from the task...
在比赛时 如果有任何选手想退出比赛...
...he or she need only send up red sparks with their wands.
...他或她只要用魔棒发送信号弹
Contestants! Gather around. Quickly!
选手们过来！快一点！
In the maze, you'll find no dragons or creatures of the deep.
在迷宫里 没有龙也没有水妖
Instead, you'll face something even more challenging.
但是有更高的挑战
You see, people change in the maze.
人会在里面发生变化
Oh, find the cup if you can.
尽量找到火焰杯
But be very wary, you could just lose yourselves along the way.
但是要小心，否则你会迷失自我
Champions, prepare yourselves!
选手们准备好！
Good luck.
好运！
- My boy. - See you later, Dad.
- 孩子 - 一会见，父亲
On the count of three. One...
我数三下，一...
Fleur?
芙蓉？
Fleur.
芙蓉
Periculum!
[咒语]
Get down!
趴下！
Expelliarmus!
[咒语]
No, don't! Stop! He's bewitched, Cedric!
不，不要，停手 他被施了巫术，塞德里克！
- Get off me! - He's bewitched!
- 让开！ - 他被施了巫术！
Yes.
好的
Harry!
哈利！
Reducto!
[咒语]
- Thanks. - No problem.
- 谢谢 - 没关系
You know, for a moment there, I thought you were gonna let it get me.
那一刻我以为你不管我了
For a moment, so did l.
那一刻我确实想过
Some game, huh?
只是一场游戏，不是吗？
Some game.
一场游戏
Go!
快跑！
Go on, take it. You saved me, take it!
去拿吧，你救了我，去拿吧
- Together. One, two... - Two...
- 一起拿，一，二... - 二...
- ...three! - ...three!
- 三！ - 三！
- You okay? - Yeah. You?
- 你没事吧？ - 没事，你呢？
Where are we?
我们在哪儿？
I've been here before.
我曾经来过这里
It's a Portkey.
他是个港口钥
- Harry, the cup is a Portkey. - I've been here before, in a dream.
- 哈利，这个杯子是个港口钥 - 在梦里我来过这里
Cedric! We have to get back to the cup. Now!
塞德里克，快回到火焰杯那里，快！
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
- Harry! What is it? - Get back to the cup!
- 哈利，那是什么？ - 快回到火焰杯那里！
- Who are you? What do you want? - Kill the spare.
- 你是谁？你想怎样？ - 干掉多余的那个
- Avada Kedavra! - No! Cedric!
- [咒语] - 不！塞德里克！
Do it! Now!
快点，现在就开始！
Bone of the father...
你父亲的骨头...
...unwillingly given.
...虽然不情愿地献出
Flesh of the servant...
奴婢的肉...
...willingly sacrificed.
...高尚的奉献
And blood of the enemy...
敌人的鲜血...
...forcibly taken.
...贪婪地吸取
The Dark Lord shall rise...
伏地魔又一次复活了...
...again.
...又一次
My wand, Wormtail.
我的魔杖，虫尾巴
Hold out your arm.
伸出你的手臂
Master.
主人
Thank you, master.
主人，谢谢
The other arm, Wormtail.
另一只手臂，虫尾巴
Welcome, my friends.
欢迎，我的朋友们
Thirteen years it's been, and yet...
已经13年了...
...here you stand before me as though it were only yesterday.
...今天你们又重新聚集在我的面前 就好象是昨天发生的一样
I confess myself...
我承认我有点...
...disappointed.
...失望
Not one of you tried to find me.
你们没有一个人试图来找寻我
Crabbe! Macnair!
克拉普丝！格鲁穆！
Goyle!
哥卢！
Not even you...
就连你...
...Lucius.
...卢修斯
My Lord, had I detected any sign, a whisper of your whereabouts...
主人，只要我有您的踪迹 或者一丝丝的传言…
There were signs, my slippery friend. And more than whispers.
有我的踪迹的，我圆滑的朋友 不仅仅是传言
I assure you, my Lord, I have never renounced the old ways.
我会证明给您看的，我的主人 我从来没有改换门庭
The face I have been obliged to present each day since your absence...
在您不在的这期间 我在众人面前的所作所为...
...that is my true mask.
...只不过是我完美的掩饰罢了
I returned.
我可是愿意回到您的身边的
Out of fear, not loyalty.
因为你害怕！不是忠心！
Still, you have proved yourself useful these past few months, Wormtail.
不过，这几个月的时间里 你至少表现出来还有点用，虫尾巴
Thank you, master.
谢谢，主人
Thank you.
谢谢
- Such a handsome boy. - Don't touch him!
- 好个帅小伙 - 别碰他！
Harry.
哈利
I'd almost forgotten you were here.
我差点都忘记你还在这里了
Standing on the bones of my father. Yeah.
站在我父亲的尸骨上
I'd introduce you...
怎么介绍你呢？
...but word has it you're almost as famous as me these days.
...这些时间以来 你都已经是和我齐名的人物了
The boy who lived.
大难不死的男孩
How lies have fed your legend, Harry.
你的传奇中有多少谎言，哈利？
Shall I reveal what really happened that night 13 years ago?
要我提醒你13年前的那个晚上 到底发生了什么吗？
Shall I divulge how I truly lost my powers?
要我道出到底是什么 让我丧失了法力么？
Yes, shall l?
是的，要我说吗？
It was love.
因为爱
You see, when dear, sweet Lily Potter gave her life for her only son...
你知道么，当那可爱的莉莉·波特 为了她唯一的儿子...
...she provided the ultimate protection.
...她给与了他终极的保护
I could not touch him.
我丝毫碰不到他
It was old magic.
那是个古老的魔法
Something I should have foreseen.
我应该预见到的
But no matter, no matter.
不过没关系，没关系
Things have changed.
一切都改变了
I can touch you...
我可以碰你了...
...now.
...现在
Yeah.
是的
Astonishing what a few drops of your blood will do, eh, Harry?
诧异你那几滴血 能给我带来那么大的转变吧，哈利
Pick up your wand, Potter.
拿起你的魔杖来，波特！
I said, pick it up! Get up! Get up!
我叫你拿起来！ 起来！起来！
You've been taught how to duel, I presume, yes?
你应该学过怎么决斗吧，是吗？
First, we bow to each other.
首先，我们要互相鞠躬
Come on, now, Harry. The niceties must be observed.
来吧，哈利 礼节是一定要遵守的
Dumbledore wouldn't want you to forget your manners, would he?
邓布利多可不想让你 忘记了自己的风度，不是吗？
I said, bow.
我说了，鞠躬
- That's better. And now... - No.
- 现在好多了，那么... - 不
Crucio!
[咒语]
Attaboy, Harry.
好孩子，哈利
Your parents would be proud.
你的父母应该为你而感到骄傲
Especially your filthy Muggle mother.
尤其是你那个麻瓜母亲
Expelliar...
[咒语]
I'm going to kill you, Harry Potter.
我要杀了你，哈利·波特
I'm going to destroy you.
我要毁了你
After tonight, no one will ever again question my powers.
过了今晚，没人再能质疑我的力量
After tonight, if they speak of you...
过了今晚 如果再有人提起你的话
...they'll speak only of how you...
...他们只可能谈起你是怎么...
...begged for death.
...苦苦求死的
And l, being a merciful Lord...
但我是个仁慈的魔头...
...obliged.
...非常仁慈
Get up!
起来！
Don't you turn your back on me, Harry Potter!
不要背对着我躲起来，哈利·波特！
I want you to look at me when I kill you!
我要你看着我是怎么杀你的！
I want to see the light leave your eyes!
我要看到光明从你的眼眸中消失
Have it your way.
那就满足你的要求
- Expelliarmus! - Avada Kedavra!
- [咒语] - [咒语]
Do nothing! He's mine to finish!
别插手，让我来结果他
He's mine!
他是我的！
Harry, when the connection is broken, you must get to the Portkey.
哈利，当法术一旦切断的时候 你必须跑到到港口钥那里
We can linger for a moment to give you some time...
我们能为你赢得一点时间...
...but only a moment. Do you understand?
...不过就一点，明白吗？
Harry, take my body back, will you?
哈利，把我的身体带回去，好么？
Take my body back to my father.
把我的身体带到我父亲身边
Let go.
切断
Sweetheart, you're ready.
亲爱的，准备好
Let go! Let go!
切断！切断吧！
Accio!
[咒语]
No!
不！
He did it!
他做到了！
Harry!
哈利！
No! No! No, don't!
不！不！不，不要！
For God's sake, Dumbledore, what's happened?
天啊，邓不利多 发生了什么？
He's back. He's back.
他回来了，他回来了！
Voldemort's back.
伏地魔复活了！
Cedric, he asked me to bring his body back.
塞德里克，他要求我 把他的身体带回来
I couldn't leave him, not there.
我不能把他留在那里
It's all right, Harry. It's all right.
没事了，哈利，没事了
He's home. You both are.
他回家了，你们两个都回家了
Keep everybody in their seats. A boy has just been killed.
让大家都坐回原位！ 有个孩子被杀了
The body must be moved, Dumbledore. There are too many people.
尸体必须被移走，邓布利多 这里有太多人了
Let me through.
让我过去
Let me through!
让我过去！
That's my son!
那是我的孩子！
That's my boy!
我的孩子！
It's my boy!
- Come on. Get up. Easy, easy! - No.
- 好了，好了，不要太难过！ - 不
This is not where you want to be right now. Come on.
现在你不应该在这儿
No!
不！
It's all right, I got you.
没事了，有我在，有我在
I got you. Come on. Easy, now.
好了，冷静点
No!
不！
不要！
Are you all right, Potter?
你还好么，波特？
Does it hurt? That?
那里还疼么？
Not so much now.
现在好多了
Perhaps I'd better take a look at it.
让我来帮你检查一下
The cup was a Portkey.
奖杯是港口钥
Someone had bewitched it.
有人给它施了魔法
What was it like?
它什么样子的？
- What was he like? - Who?
- 他长什么样子？ - 谁？
The Dark Lord.
黑暗魔头
What was it like to stand in his presence?
当你站在他面前的时候 他什么样子？
I don't know.
我不知道
It was like I'd fallen into one of my dreams...
就好象一下子掉进了 我自己的一个梦里...
...into one of my nightmares.
...一个噩梦里
Were there others?
有其他人么？
In the graveyard, were there others?
有其他人在墓地里吗？
I...
我...
I don't think I said anything about a graveyard, professor.
好像没有和你提过 关于墓地的事情吧，教授
"Marvelous creatures, dragons, aren't they? "
“龙真是一种神奇的生物，不是吗？”
Did you think that miserable oaf would've led you into the woods...
如果没有我的建议 那个傻蛋会把你带进森林么？
...if I hadn't suggested it?
如果没有我的提示？
Do you think Cedric Diggory would've told you to open the egg underwater...
你认为那个桃金娘会知道 要把金蛋放到水里吗？
...if I hadn't told him first myself?
要不是我先告诉他
Did you think Neville Longbottom, the witless wonder...
你认为纳威·隆巴顿 会找到呼吸草吗...
...could've provided you with gillyweed if I hadn't given him the book...
...如果不是我给了隆巴顿一本书 告诉他那里可以找到
...that led him straight to it?
知道吗！
It was you from the beginning. You put my name in the Goblet of Fire.
从一开始就是你 是你把我的名字放在了火焰杯里
- You bewitched Krum, but you... - "But... But..."
- 是你对克鲁姆施咒，但是你… -“但是，但是”
You won because I made it so, Potter.
你赢是因为我给你铺好了路
You ended up in that graveyard tonight because it was meant to be so.
今晚你最终会出现在那个墓地里 因为那是你注定的
And now the deed is done.
现在终于大功告成了
The blood that runs through these veins runs within the Dark Lord.
在这些血管里流过的血 是黑暗魔头的血
Imagine how he will reward me when he learns...
想象一下他会怎么好好地奖赏我 当他得知...
...that I have once and for all...
...我将会一劳永逸地...
...silenced the great Harry Potter.
...消灭了伟大的哈利·波特
Expelliarmus!
[咒语]
Severus.
西弗勒斯
That's it, take it.
就是这个，喝下去
- Do you know who I am? - Albus Dumbledore.
- 你知道我是谁么？ - 阿不思·邓不利多
- Are you Alastor Moody? Are you? - No.
- 你是不是阿拉斯托·穆迪，是不是？ - 不
Is he in this room? Is he in this room?
他在不在这个屋子里面？
Harry, away from there!
哈利，到一边去！
- You all right, Alastor? - I'm sorry, Albus.
- 你还好么，阿拉斯托？ - 我很抱歉，阿不思
That's Moody. But then who's...
他是穆迪，那么另一个是？
Polyjuice Potion.
变身水
Now we know who's been stealing from your stores, Severus.
现在我们知道是谁 偷了你储藏的药剂了，西弗勒斯
We'll get you up in a minute.
我们马上就把你弄出来
Harry!
哈利！
Barty Crouch Junior.
小巴蒂·克劳奇
I'll show you mine if you show me yours.
如果你展现给我看 我也展现给你看
Your arm, Harry.
伸出你的手臂，哈利
You know what this means, don't you?
你应该知道这意味着什么
He's back.
他复活了
Lord Voldemort has returned.
伏地魔卷土重来了
I'm sorry, sir. I couldn't help it.
对不起，老师，我没能够阻止
Send an owl to Azkaban. I think they'll find they're missing a prisoner.
让猫头鹰给阿兹卡班送信 告诉他们逃脱了一个犯人
- I'll be welcomed back like a hero. - Perhaps.
- 我将会受到英雄般的礼遇 - 也许吧
Personally, I've never had much time for heroes.
不过我个人对英雄不怎么感冒
Today, we acknowledge...
今天，我们蒙受了
...a really terrible loss.
一个无比巨大的损失
Cedric Diggory was, as you all know...
你们都认识的塞德里克·迪戈里
...exceptionally hard-working...
生前极其勤奋刻苦
...infinitely fair-minded...
公正善良
...and, most importantly...
最重要的是
...a fierce, fierce friend.
他是一个很热心的朋友
Now, I think, therefore, you have the right to know exactly how he died.
我想你们有权知道他是怎么死的
You see...
听着
...Cedric Diggory was murdered...
塞德里克·迪戈里是被
...by Lord Voldemort!
魔头伏地魔杀害的
The Ministry of Magic does not wish me to tell you this.
魔法部不希望我告诉你们真相
But not to do so, I think, would be an insult to his memory.
不过如果我不告诉你们 我会觉得那是对他的一种侮辱
Now, the pain...
这种悲痛...
...we all feel at this dreadful loss reminds me...
如今我们所共同感受到的 提醒了我
...and reminds us...
提醒了大家
...that while we may come from different places and speak in different tongues...
为什么尽管我们来自不同地方 操着不同的口音
...our hearts beat as one.
但是我们仍然万众一心
In light of recent events...
经过最近发生的事
...the bonds of friendship we've made this year will be more important than ever.
这个学期我们所建立起来的友谊 将比任何时候都重要
Remember that, and Cedric Diggory will not have died in vain.
好好记住了 塞德里克·迪戈里不会白白牺牲的
You remember that...
你们都好好记住了
...and we'll celebrate a boy who was...
我们要纪念这个男孩
...kind and honest...
一个善良的、诚实的
...and brave and true, right to the very end.
勇敢的、真诚的男孩 直至他生命的终点
I never liked these curtains.
我从来就不喜欢这些窗帘
Set them on fire in my fourth year.
四年级的时候，我曾经放火烧了它们
By accident, of course.
当然那是个意外啦
I put you in terrible danger this year, Harry. I'm sorry.
很抱歉，今年我把你置于 很危险的处境里，哈利
Professor...
教授...
...when I was in the graveyard, there was a moment...
...当我在墓地的时候 有一个时刻...
...when Voldemort's wand and mine sort of connected.
...伏地魔的魔杖和我的 在某种程度上连接在一起的时候
Priori Incantatem.
闪回咒
You saw your parents that night, didn't you?
那晚你看到了你的父母，是不是？
They reappeared.
他们又出现了
No spell can reawaken the dead, Harry. I trust you know that.
没有能够起死回生的魔咒的 你应该知道这点
Dark and difficult times lie ahead.
黑暗和困难笼罩着前行的道路
Soon we must all face the choice between what is right and what is easy.
很快我们就要在正确的 和轻松的之间进行选择
But remember this:
不过记住
You have friends here.
在这里，你有许多朋友
You're not alone.
你并不是一个人
Hermione.
赫敏
This is for you.
这是给你的
Write to me. Promise.
写信给我，答应我
Bye.
再见
Au revoir, Ron.
谢谢你，罗恩
Do you think we'll ever just have a quiet year at Hogwarts?
我们就不能在霍格沃茨 普普通通过一年吗？
- No. - No.
- 不知道 - 不知道
No, I didn't think so. Oh, well. What's life without a few dragons?
当我没说 如果生活中没有龙会怎么样？
Everything's going to change now, isn't it?
一切都要从现在开始改变了，是么？
Yes.
是的
Promise you'll write this summer. Both of you.
向我保证，这个夏天会给我写信 你们两个都要
I won't. You know I won't.
我不会的，你知道我不会的
- Harry will, won't you? - Yeah. Every week.
- 哈利，你会写的，是吧？ - 没错，每周都写